Hello everyone, my name is Rahul. Today we will
talk about what a relationship manager actually does at ICICI Bank.
Forget all the job descriptions, let's
talk about what they actually do. Before that, let's
understand what a relationship manager is and
why this position is offered to you.
Because your concept should be clear, let's
understand it with an example. If you have a
client with a high network income, what kind of
client would you be that does
n't want to come to the branch again and again? If they do
n't want to call customer care again and again, then there should be
someone to support them.
For that, a relationship manager is appointed.
He is busy
opening sales accounts, selling current
accounts, savings accounts, or other things. This
relationship manager position is
one level above a senior officer or a sales officer.
Understand everything. This is a
sought-after position in many banks. It is a very popular position.
This relationship position is not offered very quickly
because your
Communication should be very good
because you are talking to and dealing with high income individuals. At the same time,
your
selling skills should also be good. You should
maintain relationships. You should
know about banking products and services. So, the actual job of a relationship manager is to
maintain relationships with high network individual customers or companies
because they may have many queries,
many products may be retired
or you may want to
cross-sell your products or services to them. In such a situation, a
relationship manager should be appointed. He is the
point of contact. He has the
data or profile of the client for whatever needs he has.
He checks what he can sell to him and what
services he can provide. This is how
he communicates with his client.
See,
sometimes what happens in this is that a list is given to you, some
data is given, a
relationship has to be maintained, whatever business you have to do,
whatever queries you have, you have to solve them,
you have to generate sales and after that
Along with this, you also have to acquire new customers, which
means you already have a relationship,
but you also have to acquire new customers. For example, if
you open someone's
current account, then it is possible that
later he may need a credit card, a loan, or
some insurance, so you have to get all that done, which
means acquiring new customers as well.
Now let's talk about
whether this is a field job or if this work is
in the branch. Basically, this
post of a relationship manager is a
slightly higher post. In this, it is
very important for you to have knowledge of products and services
because you also have to solve the client's queries. So, it is
not like if the
bank opens at 9:00, then
you have to be in the branch from 9 to 3, then
you have to go to the field from 3 to 6, nothing like this happens, there is no
such timing,
but mostly whatever work they do, they do it through their
system and keep checking
what retirement they can get, so they work
on that, they have good knowledge,
so these are walking customers
who  Customers come to the branch and they provide service to them as well.
Like I told you, you have a
very good knowledge of these branches as well, so if
any query of a walking customer is there, then you
solve it and if a
walking customer has any need, then
you generate business by cross selling to him as well. There is nothing like this
that you have to be
in the branch from 9:00 am to 3:00 pm and
then you have to go to the sales field from 3:00 pm to 6:00 pm, so
people work in the branch,
but if you have
a customer or client who cannot come,
then you have to take an appointment and go to his
house to provide service, so this
type of field job means
you have to go to the field, but yours is a
little different, if the customer is not coming, you do
not have time, if you have a high network
customer, then you have to take an appointment and go to
him, you have to
solve his problem, if any business can be
generated from him, then if you have to generate business from him, then let's
talk about target pressure,
so the relationship manager also has target
pressure.  Because their job is
not less than that of a relationship manager, they
also have to acquire new customers, they
deal in a high network, so their
amount and figure is also a little
higher. Now let's talk about their
salary, their salary is around
24-25 rupees per month
or even more than that, but it
usually remains around this and
your salary depends on your
work location, your
experience and your background,
whatever you have. Now let's
talk about career growth,
relationship manager is a very good post, which
means you can get a promotion quickly,
if you perform well then the
promotion totally depends on your
performance and your ratings,
usually the bank gives promotion in two or
three sales, if you perform less well
then you can get a promotion quickly. The
posts related to relationship manager are
assistant manager, then DM
deputy manager, etc., so there are growth
opportunities.  It's also good, but you have to do it less
well. So, we discussed all the points about
what a post is in the ration,
but one thing I would like to tell you is that
whatever your position is in the bank, you have to
sell. You have to
bring some business. Whether you
are in a higher position or a middle position,
you still have to bring sales.
You have to acquire new customers,
cross-sell.
You have to sell all the banking products and services. No matter what
position you hold
in the bank, you still have to do this. And so,
I was thinking of
bringing a course on basic banking
for all of you. Because newcomers
who join banks or those who do
not have any banking experience or
banking background can face a
lot of problems in starting
because they do not understand small concepts
like someone asks about lien
or letter of credit or bill
remittance. On hearing these words, you do
not understand what all this is. So I am thinking of
a course on that.  Bana karke done in
which we will discuss all the things of basic banking,
so if you
want that course then please tell me in the comment below,
then I will record it and then
upload it and along with this I have
also given my style and LinkedIn profile in the about section of my channel,
so if you want to talk then you
can message me there, I hope you
understood the concept of relationship manager
and his work profile, if you liked this video
then please like and subscribe, in
future I am going to give you many more updates,
IBC all the very best till you take
care, Jai Hind